## **JATIN SHAH**

## Sales Manager

+91-7600023987 Ahmedabad, Gujarat jatinshah1986@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/jatinshah1986 Analytical, strategic-thinking sales professional with over 12 years of comprehensive experience in relationship-building, partnership cultivation, top account retainment and profit channel growth. Expertise in expanding network connections, persuasively introducing products, implementing pricing models, inventory control and projections, vendor relations and territory development. Talented at identifying customer needs to deliver effective solutions.

## **SKILLS**



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Sales Manager

### LUBI ELECTRONICS, GUJARAT

May 2014 - Present

- · Managed sales employees and counseled employees based on their professional growth and productivity.
- Researched competition and developed strategies to stand out as a company against competitors.
- Remained goal-oriented and self-motivated in every condition.
- · Handling pan India product sales and distribution network.
- · Qualified incoming team marketing and sales leads to assist with prospecting new contacts.
- Demonstrated products to customers, answered questions and redirected objectives to positive features.
- Contacted customers to immediately find resolutions for escalated issues.
- Managed customer expectations and helped navigate sales processes.
- · Monitored customer buying trends, market conditions and competitor actions to adjust strategies and achieve sales goals.
- · Supervised sales team of 2 people, stepping in to support employees and deliver smooth sales processes for clients.

### Area Sales Manager

# CONTITECH INDIA PVT LTD, GUJARAT

May 2013 - May 2014

- Established **sales goals** by **forecasting** annual sales quotas and projecting expected sales volume for existing and new products.
- Identified and maximized sales opportunities and increased customer retention rates.
- Continually generated sales throughout the area and aided to increase geographic presence.
- · Consistently surpassed sales quotas by implementing effective sales strategies.
- Implemented Search and develop top key accounts as per company policy.
- Instrumental in to develop and execute strategic plans to achieve sales targets and expand company's customer base.
- · Showed Good communication with aggressive attitude Strong persuasive skills and ability to influence decision makers.

### Sales Engineer

### LUBI ELECTRONICS, GUJARAT

Sep 2011 - May 2013

Worked out sales activities and strategies based on annual sales target

Managed key accounts sales

Co-ordinated sales activities with regional sales teams, distributors

Ensure best possible after sales services to KEY ACCOUNTS

#### Sales Executive

## VIVANTE PUREFOODS PVTLTD, GUJARAT

May 2010 - Sep 2011

- Identified and maximized sales opportunities, and increased customer retention rates.
- Surpassed sales quotas by implementing effective sales strategies and equipping providers with powerful product knowledge.
- Led sales department with a can-do attitude and high quarterly sales.
- · Tracked, measured and reported on trends for sales team analysis and decision making.

• Demonstrated products to customers, answered questions and redirected objectives to positive features.

## **EDUCATION**

MBA: SALES AND N R INSTITUTE OF BUSINESS Grade: MARKETING DEVELOPMENT FIRST

BE-MECHANICAL C K PITHAWALA COLLEGE OF Grade: ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY FIRST

## **REFERENCE**

PRATIK JARIWALA SALES MANAGER SCHNIEDER ELECTRIC pratik.jariwala@lntebg.com 9925647457